<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="Docometre.feature"
      label="Feature"
      version="1.0.0.qualifier"
      provider-name="ISM">

   <description>
      -- 2023-03-14
ADDED :
* Add licence option to Matlab command line
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2023-03-13
ADDED :
* Import data from text files organized in column
* Change message error color
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2023-02-27
ADDED :
* CR and LF options in Serial Output function (ADWin)
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2023-02-13
ADDED :
* Improve serial output functions : now can handle literals and
channels
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2023-02-12
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* Support for string parameters (use \n as seprator char)
-- 2023-02-10
ADDED :
* Support for string parameters
FIXED :
* NPE in adwin dacq configuration pages
* Bad functions absolute path initialization (Adwin and ArduinoUno)
-- 2023-02-07
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Remove moduleNumber parameter for Adwin Gold devices (Write
FLOAT RS232 function)
-- 2023-02-06
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Remove moduleNumber parameter for Adwin Gold devices (Write
ASCII chars RS232 function)
-- 2023-01-24
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Update site URL move from univmed to univ-amu
-- 2023-01-13
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* dispose display at shutdown
-- 2023-01-09
ADDED : 
* Save worksapce dialog data and return exit code
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2023-01-09
ADDED : 
* Save worksapce dialog data and return exit code
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2023-01-09
ADDED : 
* Improve export script code (Matlab)
FIXED : 
* Syntax error in exported script code (Python)
-- 2023-01-07 - Bis
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* Remove test code (Docometre.py)
-- 2023-01-07
ADDED :
* Report progress with progress service (Save all action)
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2023-01-07
ADDED :
* Update workbench when Math Engine pref is changed
FIXED :
* Wrong index for end value (MAXIMUM.FUN, Matlab)
* Wrong index for trial number (TIME_MARKER.FUN, Matlab)
* Wrong End cut value when current values size is bigger (loadDataDocometre,
Matlab)
-- 2023-01-06
ADDED :
* Remember last trials list for all functions
* Add warning message if process resource does not exist (RunBatchDataProcessingDelegate)
* Change intro text
* Matplotlib must run in Main thread (Python engine - JVM mode)
* Block until a callback is available (Python engine - JVM mode)
FIXED :
* Channel, 2D and 3D chart editors are not persistent 
* Dot not try to deserialize if it&apos;s a channel (ObjectsController)
* Do not enable rename action if selected resource is channel
(RenameResourceAction)
* NPE if process resource does not exist (ExportScriptWizard)
-- 2022-12-12
ADDED :
* Support for network port numbers management with Python Math.
Engine
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-12-09 - BIS
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Index Out Of Bounds exception in Find Amplitude Forward 
-- 2022-12-09
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Clear error message when selection changes (Export Markers
and Features functions)
-- 2022-12-08
ADDED :
* Expression function : add/improve content assistants (Source
viewer and expressions)
FIXED :
* Expression function : increase horizontal Spacing to show decoration
icon
* Expression function : add error message if Math. Engine is
not started
-- 2022-12-06
ADDED :
* Export batch processing script code to file
FIXED :
* Don&apos;t add modified decorator if subject is not loaded
* Update batch data processing when subject or process is renamed
-- 2022-11-23
ADDED:
* It is now possible to run single process in Batch data proc.
editor
* Dialog to be able to save several subjects at a time
* Export features function (Matlab and Python) 
FIXED :
* Update signal editor (sample freq., front/end cuts) 
* Ignore unknown elements in XML files
* Don&apos;t run batch process if math. engine is not running
-- 2022-11-19
ADDED :
* Export Markers function : add support for relative/absolute
dest.
* Markers difference function (Matlab and Python)
* Markers difference function set initial selection for difference
type
* Show samples and Keep scale when trials change in signals editors
FIXED :
* Bad trial number with Python (indices start form zero with
Python)
* Export Markers function : turn widget field to transient for
serialization
* Motion distance function : index correction
* Remove pulses function : clear SignalSizes variable
* Export Markers function : clear several variables
* Export Markers function : NPE
* Don&apos;t use cells anymore with features (Matlab)
* Clear pulses function : message refactoring
* Find amplitude forward : index bug correction
-- 2022-11-07
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* We don&apos;t need to compile data processing processes (Compile
Dialog)
-- 2022-11-04
ADDED :
* Support for cached logging before messages view activation
* Improve Error and Standard log file redirection
* Add support for auto/manual build switch
FIXED :
* Remove System.out
* NPE in DataProcessEditor.java
* Graphic is disposed in DocometreAnnotationAccesExtension.java
-- 2022-10-21
ADDED :
* Persistence for link with editor action view (Experiments view)
* Persistence for editors
FIXED : Nothing 
-- 2022-10-20
ADDED :
* Stimulus recording and visualization are now allowed
* Improve script connection router
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-10-18 - Bis
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Add Support for stimuli for ADwin variables - End
-- 2022-10-18
ADDED : 
* Experiments view link with editors
FIXED :
* Layout management in Module pages 
-- 2022-10-13 - QUATER
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* Update help
-- 2022-10-13 - TER
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* Enhance Modules observers management
-- 2022-10-13 - BIS
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* Remove duplicate backed channels in RS232 modules
* NPE in RS232 modules
-- 2022-10-13
ADDED :
* ADBasic Compilation on OSX using Docker is now working
* Help updated 
FIXED : 
* Class cast and NPE exceptions
-- 2022-10-12 - Bis
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* ADBasic compile error (Could not find a SUB with the specified
name. write_fifo())
-- 2022-10-12
ADDED :
* Support for stimuli for ADwin variables - Step 3
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-10-11 - Bis
ADDED :
* Support for stimuli for ADwin variables - Step 2
FIXED :
* Floating point exception when frequency of RS232 module is
empty
* Synchro chars CR+LF were not send when using ICE system
-- 2022-10-11
ADDED : 
* Support for ICE with RS232 module
* Support for stimuli for ADwin variables (Step 1)
* &quot;Remove pulses&quot; function (Maltab @ Python)
FIXED :
* Wrong tooltips editors
* NPE for description property (New/Edit Resource Wizard)
* Remove code from description (Expression function)
-- 2022-09-29 - Bis
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Default suffix for output signal was wrong (ReplaceSamples
function)
-- 2022-09-29
ADDED :
* Improve replace Samples function initialization
* Color management for category editor
FIXED :
* NPE with memento init. or restore view
* Wrong function in clone method (ReplaceSamples function)
* V. and H. scrolls are now available (Expression function)
-- 2022-09-27
ADDED :
* Threshold function (Matlab &amp; Python)
* Replace samples function (Matlab only)
FIXED :
* Improve exception message
* Bug in Maximum function error (Matlab only)
-- 2022-09-26
ADDED :
* Expermiments view save state
* Expression function (Matlab &amp; Python)
FIXED :
* Derivative function : add zero at signal beginning not end
-- 2022-07-26
ADDED :
* Subjects view save state
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-07-25
ADDED :
* Change sample frequency function
FIXED :
* Return proper tool tip for channel editor function
(Python)
-- 2022-07-11
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Resize data if trials have not always same number of samples
(Python)
-- 2022-07-08
ADDED :
* Add support for ADW data files to Python Math. engine 
FIXED :
* Resolve Bugs on params parsing and wrong dialog layout
* Wrong Front cut intial value (0 not 1)
-- 2022-07-05 - Bis
ADDED :
* Auto select newly added marker in Signal editor
* Help update for Optitrack type 1 data files 
* Add support to import subjects from Optitrack type 1 data files
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-07-05
ADDED :
* Support for functions editor
* Support for functions view
* Font size increase/decrease support in text editors 
* Stop math engine when App. is closed and action is not canceled
* Add reportNonDisposed=false JVM argument to docometre.ini file
FIXED :
* Bug correction on mean computation (Matlab only)
* Don&apos;t stop MathEngine if save subject is canceled
* Bug reading Functions text files
* NPE in Resource editor input
* Enable setType menu item only if selected part is experimentView
* Remove excess backslash in Find amplitude backward and forward
* Bug when customer function was renamed
* Bug on user (customer) functions files saving
* Do not manage Handles for user functions
-- 2022-06-18
ADDED :
* Trust Pref. Page translation (continued)
* It&apos;s now possible to cancel &quot;unload&quot; subject action
FIXED :
* Force default systems property values if not already performed
* Error message refacoring in several Matlab functions
* Save and Save all commands bad behaviour
* Retrieve channel from its full name not only from provided
experiment
-- 2022-06-14 - Bis
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* a bug where it was impossible to save subject
-- 2022-06-14
ADDED :
* Update Help
* New Trust Pref. Page translation 
FIXED :
* Refactoring in Matlab and Python scripts
* Bug if &quot;ans&quot; variable exists calling &quot;getLoadedSubjects&quot; (Matlab
only) 
-- 2022-06-07
ADDED :
* Shortcut &apos;D&apos; for &apos;docometre.experiments&apos; (Python)
FIXED :
* Bad URI exception when paste from clipboard
-- 2022-06-03
ADDED :
* Improve automatic color selection in charts
* Move to Eclipse 03 2022 release
FIXED :
* IOOBException in XYZ charts (End Cut can be greater than points
size)
* Change painting order in signals charts
* Java 11 requirement for Py4j and o.e.ui.cheatsheets
* Some refactoring for deprecation 
* Can now run data processing when source tab is selected
-- 2022-05-31
ADDED :
* Support for marker selection in signal editor
* Interpolate 1-D function 
* Duplication signal function
* Print Math engine version at start up
* Categories management to 2D and 3D Charts
* Categories labels near trials numbers in Signal editors
FIXED :
* Wrong default suffix interpolate function
* Check if it&apos;s Optitrack type 1 and not only data files when
loading subject to call optitrack loading method
-- 2022-05-20
ADDED :
* Export Markers function (Matlab and Python)
FIXED :
* Float type was not handled when loading/saving subject (Python)
* Properly update workbench when data is processed
* Take multiple markers in account in Faf, Fab functions (Matlab,Python)
* In batch data processing, save/unload subject is now taken
in account
* Transfert function : now all markers are transferred
* Set Selection provider in Source Viewer (Copy from source viewer
is now working !) 
-- 2022-05-12
ADDED :
* Support for code source editor in epxressions function
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-05-11 - Bis
ADDED :
* Add support for external paste files
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-05-11
ADDED :
* Matlab functions : find peaks (max and min) and absolute value
* Python functions : find peaks min
* Display message when trying to add marker whereas cursor is
not active
* Update source viewers automatically
* Update show cursor property in opened editors
* Shifting of the blocks during paste
FIXED :
* Add forgotten &quot;import scipy&quot; in FIND_PEAKS python function
-- 2022-05-05 - Ter
FIXED :
* Bug on replacing back slash on windows (tested before !)
-- 2022-05-05 - Bis
FIXED :
* Bug on replacing back slash on windows
-- 2022-05-05
ADDED :
* Find peaks function
-- 2022-05-02
ADDED :
* Support for Optitrack CSV data files with Markers only. Matlab
and Python.
FIXED : 
* Wrong button style (SWT) in 2D and 3D charts
* Bug in SelectChannelsWizard in perform finish 
-- 2022-04-22 - Bis
ADDED : nothing
FIXED : 
* RS_RESET and RS_INIT was not done on RS232 interface for ADwin
gold
-- 2022-04-22
ADDED : nothing
FIXED : 
* Return code for comment blocks must be empty string not null
-- 2022-04-04
ADDED : Proper icon for unknown resource type 
FIXED : nothing
-- 2022-03-31
ADDED : 
* Support for user function to Math Engines
* Support for Docker (Adwin on Mac OS 10.15 and more)
FIXED :
* Need double backslash in reg. exp. parameters (user functions)
-- 2022-03-25
ADDED : 
* Protocol importation feature (Issue #10)
* Import resource enhancement
* Error message enhancement 
* Help pages enhancement
* Change about dialog text 
* Support for custom/user function
FIXED :
* Bug where subject with almost same name are unloaded (Python)
* Bug on files validation when importing subjects or experiments
-- 2022-02-23
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Time values are no longer in samples files (Arduino Uno)
* Error in duration computation (Signal Editor)
-- 2022-02-21
ADDED :
* Update Acknowlegements
FIXED :
* Bad display on New/Edit Session Wizard
-- 2022-02-10
ADDED : 
* Sample frequency dialog when data editor do not find one
FIXED :
* Bug in Stimulus initialization 
-- 2022-02-9 - Bis
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Initialize time to zero (ADwin and Uno)
-- 2022-02-9
ADDED :
* Adwin/Arduino/Python/Matlab files are now in Libraries plug-in
* Header comments to user functions (ADwin and Arduino Uno)
* Stimulus feature
* Analog and Digital Wait functions
* Transfert function
FIXED :
* Libraries path now comes from default pref. not from dacq.
conf.
* ADwin, Arduino Uno, Matlab and Python preferences changes
* Bug when a resource is renamed and not opened : must deserialize
it
* When exporting experiment, sytem type was lost for Log files.
This property is now written in properties file
-- 2022-01-26
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Build message internationalization
-- 2022-01-25
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Bad indentation for variables transfer code (Arduino)
-- 2022-01-21
ADDED : 
* Internationalization for ADwin
* Apply &quot;show Cursor/Marker&quot; immediately to all Signal Editors
FIXED : 
* Add user library support for Arduino Uno on Linux and Windows
Plat.
* Message correction when compilation has succeeded
* Proper management of the page&apos;s validity 
-- 2022-01-11 - Ter
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* Wrong default location for Matlab and Python Scripts
-- 2022-01-11 - Bis
ADDED :
* Update preferences (again!)
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-01-11
ADDED :
* Update preferences (again)
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-01-10
ADDED :
* Update preferences 
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-01-07 - Bis
ADDED :
* Set workbench window maximized at first launch
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2022-01-07
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Bug at start up when &quot;.medata&quot; folder does not exist
-- 2022-01-06
ADDED :
* Add support for XML serialization using XStream library
* Set default serialization to XML
* Use workspace locker file to prevent several session to open
same workspace
* It is now possible to start a new Docometre Session on Mac
OS X
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2021-12-20
ADDED : 
* Main menu refactoring
FIXED :
* Detach entry in contextual view/editor menu translation 
-- 2021-12-14
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Remove comment code for customer function when segment is empty
-- 2021-12-13 - Ter
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Regression in workbench shared images
-- 2021-12-13 - Bis
ADDED :
* Marquee tools in process editors with fr translations
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2021-12-13
ADDED :
* Update description view when trials states change
* Missing space in selected resource label
* Improve Sleak view presentation
FIXED :
* Resource leaks with data editor 
-- 2021-12-09
ADDED : 
* Clean build capability. Called before any compilation, renamed
or deleted process resource
FIXED :
* Resource leaks on images management
* Update editors when process is renamed or deleted
-- 2021-12-08
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : Build problem (files not deployed !)
-- 2021-12-07
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED : 
* Get script code generation even if it&apos;s not a script segment
* Solve blocking compilation condition
* Remove duplicate binaryMedian lib. function declaration in
DocoLib (ADWin)
-- 2021-12-06 - Bis
ADDED :
* Toggle real time charts view visibility between trials 
FIXED : 
* Suppress NLS unused Warning messages
-- 2021-12-06
ADDED :
* Improve Arduino Uno management (now use interrupt and improve
data transfer, analog inputs and ADS1115 module management)
* Elements in online help and cheat sheets
* User libraries Arduino preference path 
FIXED : 
* Too long time response with editors (optimize method time response
: getResourceForObject())
* Bug on gain selection for ADS1115 module 
-- 2021-11-19
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Fixed a Bug in Cursor and Marker paint control listener 
-- 2021-11-18
ADDED :
* Support for 3D chart editor
* Support for debugging tools 
* Improvement on QuickStart tutorial
* QuickStartCheatSheet updates
* IP addresses gatherer for adwin dacq. conf. 
FIXED :
* SWT Resource leak : font not disposed (CursorMarkerDeltaPainter.java)
* Many refactoring
* Arduino Real time loop enhancement (micros() : 1us (Portenta),
4us (Uno) drift)
* Remove arduino wdt to stop board : simply use exit(0) instead
* Change default arduino global frequency to 100Hz
-- 2021-10-14
ADDED :
* Support for 3D chart editor - Step 1 
* Allow Wine file path pref to be empty
FIXED :
* Bug when a channel is suppressed : transfer numbers were not
updated
-- 2021-10-11 - Bis
ADDED :
* Disable p2 garbage collector
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2021-10-11
ADDED : 
* ADS1115 module to Arduino Uno
* Select all capability to SourceEditor 
* Improve FindDialog management and behaviour
* Update Help 
* Remove Unit, unit and ampli. min and max in analog inputs (Arduino
Uno and ADS1115 module)
FIXED : 
* Bug on first sample line series drawing (Time and XY Charts)
* Optimize Resource listeners when process compilation is started
(UI responsiveness)
-- 2021-09-22
ADDED : 
* All Python DSP functions have been ported to Matlab
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2021-09-15
ADDED : 
* Butt. high pass, front &amp; end cut, Derivate, front &amp; end cut
from marker to Matlab engine
* Managing some prefs. values at first App. launch
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2021-09-08
ADDED : 
* Sort customer functions enhancement
FIXED :
* Remove .gitignore from ADwin CUSTOMER_FUNCTIONS
-- 2021-09-02
Added :
* Sort customer functions
Fixed : Nothing
-- 2021-06-10
Added :
* Add small margin width in XY Chart right composites
Fixed :
* Remove spinner parent set focus to prevent button selection
-- 2021-06-09
Added :
* Use same color form same category trials (Time and XY charts)
Fixed :
* Bugs on Import/Export experiment and subjects wizards 
-- 2021-06-07
Added :
* Support to export only selected subjects from an experiment
* Support to import only selected exported subjects (Step 1)
Fixed :
* Bug in displaying Markers : X and Y axis where swapped
* Add Debug Messages to experiment exportation
-- 2021-06-03 - Bis
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* use font style setter instead of direct field access (Maven
build failed)
-- 2021-06-03
ADDED :
* Handle Standard and Error outputs redirection to file
* Extend &quot;Set type&quot; Experiment View context menu to all types
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2021-06-02
ADDED :
* Add custom functions for ISM chair command
FIXED :
* Fix IOOBE in RTSWTChartOscillo
-- 2021-06-01
ADDED :
* XY Chart Editor enhancement
* XY Chart Editor persistence
* Support for horizontal reference in OScillo. Chart
* Use Eclipse Theme
* Upgrade to Java 11
* Upgrade JSSC
* Support for Tank and Gauge Charts
FIXED :
* Fix NPE bug (when platform was brutally closed and reopening
while editors was opened)
* Control decoration bad behavior in resources creation wizard
(show/hide)
-- 2021-05-20
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Bug With base front cuts in XY Chart editor
-- 2021-05-19 - Bis
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Fix bug with front cut other than zero
-- 2021-05-19
ADDED : Nothing
FIXED :
* Fix OOBE when front/end cuts are taken in account
-- 2021-05-18
ADDED :
* Support for displaying Markers in XY Chart editor
* Improve zoom and chart parameters handlers in XY Chart editor
* Add support for Zoom listeners in interactive chart
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2021-05-17
ADDED :
* Write Delay value for Arduino Uno in preferences
* Add support for Range and front/end cuts managements in XY
Chart
* XY chart persistence
FIXED :
* Check if chart name already exists for chart renaming or creation
* X, Y were switched in XY Chart !
-- 2021-05-05
ADDED :
* Log error message when Serial Port Exception
* Add a small delay (10us) after each Serial.println
FIXED :
* Retrieve right indexes from data files for Arduino Uno
* Fix a bug when locale is different from exported locale
* Use portable string when creating properties file for exportation
* Use &quot;/&quot; instead of File.separator as it is platform dependent
* Process one more sample (Motion direction)
* Copy Front and End Cut in new created signal (Motion Distance)
-- 2021-05-03
ADDED :
* XY Chart Support (Step 1)
FIXED : Nothing
-- 2021-05-02
ADDED :
* Some enhancement in session wizard pages 
* Allow &quot;_&quot; char in data and data batch processing file name
FIXED :
* Display current value now works properly for Oscillo charts
* Manage operators for ADBasic, C, Python and Matlab
-- 2021-04-30
ADDED :
* Transfer Markers Group function (Python)
* Motion Direction function (Python)
FIXED :
* Change default suffix in Motion Distance function (Python)
-- 2021-04-29 - BIS
FIXED :
* bug where temporaryBuffer declared several times when floats
are transfered (Arduino Uno)
-- 2021-04-29
ADDED :
* Find Amplitude backward and forward to python functions
* Add Front and End cut from marker functions (Python)
* Add Font and display current value support to Oscillo and XY
charts
FIXED :
* Markers group number was wrong when deleting it (Signal editor)
* Channel name was wrong when &quot;use prefix&quot; Session property is
false
* Some functions titles refactoring
* Manage some errors when front cut is greater than end cut
-- 2021-04-27 - BIS
FIXED :
* Channel name was wrong when &quot;use prefix&quot; Session property is
empty
* Use num.copy to avoid &quot;pointer effect&quot; with numpy array assignment
-- 2021-04-27
ADDED :
* Minimum and Maximum Python functions
FIXED :
* Process editor force update
* TIMER_MARKER function : trialsList was hard coded to 0:417
!
-- 2021-04-23
ADDED :
* Add Motion Distance function (Python)
* Add Time Marker function (Python)
* Add Derivative function (Python)
FIXED :
* Use default parameters in functions
* Add CR to each end python functions (clearly separate each
functions in script)
* Update selection service in Subjects View
-- 2021-04-16
ADDED :
* vectorize endcut and frontcut 
* Set Charts dialog layout modeless
* Functions menu internationalization
* Add Front Cut and End Cut functions (python only for now) 
* Add Butterworth high pass filter to python engine 
FIXED :
* ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException: Index 0 out of bounds for length
0 (RTSWChartOscillo)
* JRE and compiler compliance to 1.8 (Theme plugin)
* Python functions enhancement (remove gateway System.out)
* Update cache channels when channel is deleted
* Some enhancement in python functions and code scanner 
* Managing load/Save/Unload subject with batch processing
* Bad style in chart options Group preferences
* Front and End cut where not taken in account in time vector
creation 
* Manage bug when path to Docometre.py is wrong 
-- 2021-04-9
ADDED :
Some Console Messages for python controller
-- 2021-04-7
ADDED : 
* Improve description message in Function Configuration Dialog
* Improve process random spreading (never two same consecutive
trials)
* Default python time out from 10 to 15 sec.
FIXED :
* Bug when starting Python Engine on Windows (use now portable
strings)
* Internationalization : some strings unused some others missing
* Import Wizard : NPE if folder is empty
* Import Wizard : Do not apply property if resource does not
exist
* Bug on time out evaluation in Python Controller
-- 2021-03-24
ADDED :
* It is now possible to export experiment with or without data
files
* Improve export wizard description message
* Improve export progress monitor
FIXED :
* Code generation bug where If and Do blocks where not taken
in account
-- 2021-03-19
ADDED :
* Export data wizard
* Support for comment in processes (ADWin, Arduino Uno, Matlab,
Python)
* Support for Python syntax coloring editor
FIXED :
* Wrong markers group number in MathEngine
* Channels Container Refactoring
-- 2021-02-15
ADDED :
* Support for features in MathEngine
* Error management  to MathEngine scripts
* Mean function
* Channels choices improvements in functions
* Cache support for channel management
Fixed :
* Bug correction on multiple &quot;#INCLUDE ADWPEXT.INC&quot;
* NbMarkers and NbFields correction to NbMarkersGroups and NbFeatures
in data model
-- 2021-01-25 -- BIS
FIXED :
* NPE on monitor cancellation
ADDED :
* Show message when channel used by any function cannot be found
* Batch data processing editor (data model, GUI and Undo/Redo)
* Ask to stop MathEngine before allowing workbench shutdown
FIXED :
* CAN Module page was always marked dirty when opened.
* Bug correction when a paste resource has file extension
ADDED :
* Add Math Engine view
* Save subject without Exp.Subj prefix - Load adding Exp.Subj
prefix
* Add support to handle transmit/receive mode and multiple message
IDs in CAN module
* Update Math engine when subject/experiment is loaded and renamed
* Unload experiment in Math engine when it is deleted
* Update Exp. and Subj. view once a launched data processing
has finished
* Manage indentation for Arduino/ADWin - Matlab/Python
* Remove blocking error message when configuring function
pref. 
* Add support for live Math engine type changes : don&apos;t need
to restart anymore
FIXED :
* Bug correction on retrieving created or modified channels
* FrontCut &amp; EndCut correction for Matlab Engine
* Bug correction on numpy data files path
* Some NPE
-- 2020-10-21 --
ADDED :
* Print custom function label in generated process code
* Support for Python Engine 
* Support for markers
* Support for Modified/Save/Load/Unload subject
* Allow subject to be loaded from raw or saved data
* Move default math engine pref. from general pref. to math engine
pref. 
* Support for show marker and cursor preferences 
* Unload subject before stopping math engine
* When subject is unloaded, close all related editors
* Ask to record changes before unloading modified subject 
* Support for previous and next trial in channel editors
* Use Progress Monitor Dialog to load/unload subjects
FIXED :
-- 2020-09-09 -- BIS
ADDED :
* Support for comments in parameters files (ADWin)
-- 2020-09-09 --
ADDED :
* Support for SAMPLES Files with Matlab engine
* Improve category container layout
FIXED :
* Bug where not all trials could have been taken in categories
-- 2020-07-23 --
ADDED :
* Improve Math Engines Preferences pages
* Improve user information when open, delete, import, export
etc. for long operation
* Data processing prespective : 
&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; Subjects and channels View
&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; Channels editor (Signals with cursor and Categories)
&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; Data processing editor
* Support for 3D Chart with JZY3D third library
* &quot;Associate with&quot; menu item for process test
* Allow Root workspace refresh (empty selection in view)
* Support for channel deletion
* Refresh Subjects view when a data processing had run
* First data processing : Butterworth matlab lowpass filter
* Change Eclipse RCP repository to 2020-06
* Math engine for Matlab
* Support for ADW file import and loading in Matlab Engine
* CeCILL-B Licences
* Organize session
FIXED :
* Bug correction when export experiment file name is not the
same as original one
* Delete temporary properties file when importing experiment
* Add ASS. PRO. FILE. for process test folder in properties files
when exporting experiment
* Bug on IResource Path on mac os
* Init. cursor and marker coordinates to empty String to avoid
NPE (Interactive Chart)
* Set marker coordinates to nearest sample in series
* NPE on Clean, Reset Trials and Toggle Trial Start Mode handlers
-- 2020-03-11 -- 
ADDED :
* Improve paste resources action
* Add error marker in Arduino Diary
FXED :
Nothing
-- 2020-03-05 -- QUATER
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Manage OS dependent Path when importing experiment
-- 2020-03-05 -- TER
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* ADwin preManageParameters : now handle NPE or NFE on parse
float
* ADwin preManageParameters : correct parameters logging when
running trial
-- 2020-03-05 --
ADDED :
* Log parameters values before runnning process test or trial
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2020-03-04 -- TER
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Bug on Subject without any session (zero trials)
-- 2020-03-04 -- BIS
ADDED :
* Add Binary median filter function for ADWin
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2020-03-04 --
ADDED :
* Change Comment block colors
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2020-03-02 --
ADDED :
* default blue theme
* Update Welcome/Intro
* Install Arduino cheatsheet
* Start Session organisation wizard
* Default cheatsheets updates
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2020-02-11 --
ADDED :
* Add progress information on subject/session description view
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2020-02-09 --
ADDED :
* Add percent done for Subject/Session in experiment view
* Initial Pi4j support and Python Controller creation
* Update several Vendors ID in Manifest files projects
FIXED :
* Initialize each CAN module channels&apos;s to zero to avoid random
first value (ADWin)
-- 2020-02-05 --
ADDED :
* Now handle customer function code generation
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2020-02-04 --
ADDED :
* Refresh selected resources when they are cleaned up
* Manage undone trials when we are in acquisition mode/perspective
FIXED :
* Bug fix on Arduino : port busy on OSX
-- 2020-02-03 --
ADDED :
* Comment block support in process
* Improve import menu availability
* Improve experiment description management
* Support for exporting experiment
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2020-01-27 --
ADDED :
* Customized functions are now handled
* Start documentation for sutomized function
* Upgrade to Eclipse 12 2019 platform
* Matlab Engine and Controller plugins
* Now possible to change resource type
* Now possible to change system type on DAcq resource
* Improve import resource wizard
FIXED :
* Chart is flipped vertically on Mac OS when saved as image
* Bug on objects nb handles management
* Bug in Byte Serial Input Function (ADWin)
* Layout correction in JVLMAC141WriteRegisterValueFunction (ADWin)
* Bug on platform shared Image in Docometre Activator
* Bug while compiling when no associated DAcq resource is found
* Default ADWin and Arduino Uno Prefs. are now populated at first
launch
-- 2019-12-09 -- QUINQUIES
ADDED :
* Add Actual Position to available registers in JVL_MAC141 functions
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2019-12-09 -- QUATER
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Bug in JVL_MAC141_CHANGE_MODE.FUN
-- 2019-12-09 -- TER
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Once command sent, wait to read three &quot;11H&quot; values in JVL_MAC141_CHANGE_MODE.FUN
-- 2019-12-09 -- BIS
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Bug correction in JVL_MAC141_READ_REGISTER_VALUE.FUN
-- 2019-12-09 --
ADDED :
* Add frame processing to compute register value in JVL_MAC141_READ_REGISTER_VALUE.FUN
FIXED :
* Once command sent, wait to read three &quot;11H&quot; values in JVL_MAC141_WRITE_REGISTER_VALUE.FUN
-- 2019-12-02 -- QUATER
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Double &quot;)&quot; bug correction in JVL_MAC141_READ_REGISTER_VALUE.FUN
-- 2019-12-02 -- TER
ADDED :
* Add JVL Mac141 Servo motor read register function (ADWin)
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2019-12-02 -- BIS
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Print saved register key value in text widget [JVL Mac141 Servo
motor write register function (ADWin)]
-- 2019-12-02 --
ADDED :
* Add JVL Mac141 Servo motor change mode function (ADWin)
* Add JVL Mac141 Servo motor write register function (ADWin)
FIXED :
* Remove \n at the end of adbasic Header to retrieve proper line
numbers (erros, warnings)
-- 2019-11-19 --
ADDED :
* Add support for channels in Byte Serial Output function
(ADWin Pro)
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2019-11-13 --
ADDED :
* Add support for multiple writes in Byte Serial Output function
(ADWin Pro)
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2019-11-12 --
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Change ASCII serial functions to Byte serial functions (ADWin
Pro)
-- 2019-11-5 BIS --
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* Take LongSerialOutputFunction into account in order to add
String library to ADBasic Code
-- 2019-11-5 --
ADDED :
Nothing
FIXED :
* ADWin RS232 proper message and value for integer
-- 2019-10-15 --
ADDED :
* Cheat sheet support
FIXED :
Nothing
-- 2019-10-09 --
ADDED :
* Renaming subject, session or trial can now affect data files
names
* Allow copy even if resource name already exists using _Copy_n
suffix
* Clean action to remove log and data files
* Close editors, if necessary, when parent resource is deleted
* Ask for log and data files deletion when resource is paste
* Update Edition main menu bar with existing menu items
FIXED :
* Remove error message when a resource is renamed and previous
resource no longer exists
* Add correct suffix in data name example
* Data files have .sample extension not .sau in data name example
* Always use trial number as suffix in data files names (Session
properties)
* Bug fix when child resource is not a container when renaming
parent resource
-- 2019-10-06 --
ADDED :
* Redraw only necessary area in data editor
* Add little square to cursor to show data point in series
* Remove ata editor Marker when necessary
* Add cursor, marker and delta status line contribution items
* Chart menu items internationalization
* Add chart cursor and marker support to SWT Chart in Data Editor
FIXED :
* Nice tooltip data editor
* Set Workload/Time Contribution item visibility depending on
perspective ID
-- 2019-09-30 --
ADDED :
* Use SWT Chart for data editors
FIXED :
* Fix bug on DACQ handler numbers when compile is started
* Activate import action only in design perspective
-- 2019-09-20 BIS --
ADDED :
* Version qualifier to main Window
FIXED :
* Nothing
-- 2019-09-20 --
ADDED :
* Show and allow changes of channels numbers in Arduino Uno modules
FIXED :
* Nothing
-- 2019-09-16 BIS --
ADDED :
* Nothing
FIXED :
* Fix bug in Data file Path on Windows
-- 2019-09-16 --
ADDED :
* Nothing
FIXED :
* Allow &quot;_&quot; in channels names
-- 2019-09-13 --
ADDED :
* Arduino Digital Input function support
* Arduino Digital output function support
FIXED :
* test equality bug in Arduino process (convert = to == for if
and do
blocks)
* Move startTime init. to the end of init. algo. for arduino
process
* Manage code generation and indentation for Arduino
-- 2019-09-10 --
ADDED :
* taking pause key into account for PC
* taking pause into account for MAC using &quot;CMD + P&quot; 
* Add specific status line contribution for Workload and time
informations
* Add specific status line contribution for pause information
FIXED :
* Nothing
-- 2019-09-09 --
ADDED :
* Nothing
FIXED :
* Initialize PAR_n to avoid wrong error data loss message (ADWin)
* No Border for Value Label in Digital Output Function
-- 2019-09-05 -- TER
ADDED :
* Nothing
FIXED :
* Add ADwpAD.inc to include files
-- 2019-09-05 -- BIS
ADDED :
* Nothing
FIXED :
* Add SE_DIFF directive for ADwinPro in Calibration
-- 2019-09-05 --
ADDED :
* Nothing
FIXED :
* Add SE_DIFF directive for ADwinPro
-- 2019-09-04 --
ADDED :
* Update Docometre.feature file (information tab)
FIXED :
* Nothing
-- 2019-09-03 --
ADDED :
* Add literal value to Digout function
* Show text on perspective bar by default
FIXED :
* Delete process test folder if exists when a process is tested
* Replace &quot;_&quot; with &quot;.&quot; in process test folder data files names
-- 2019-07-22 --
ADDED :
* Increase figure tool tip max. width to 1000px
FIXED :
* Nothing
-- 2019-07-19 --
ADDED :
* Import wizard (Process and DACQ Conf.)
FIXED :
* Copy/Paste bug correction
* RegExp Bug correction in ADBasic source editor when replacing
ADbasic Header
-- 2019-07-10 --
ADDED :
* Show error message if next trial has no associated process
FIXED :
* Bug correction on reading DIO input value
-- 2019-06-27 BIS --
ADDED :
* Nothing
FIXED :
* Fixed bug preventing an adwin dacq configuration creation when
revision is not specified (default ADwin system) 
-- 2019-06-27 --
ADDED :
* Read initial analog values in calibration dialog
FIXED :
* Nothing
-- 2019-06-26 BIS --
ADDED :
* Nothing
FIXED :
* Bug on ADWinPro Calibration files (par_9 is returning to 0)
* Bug on DIO module in/out configuration (Digprog1 and Digprog2)
-- 2019-06-26 --
ADDED :
* Add Revision management to module (Pro DIO Modules)
FIXED :
* Nothing
-- 2019-06-25 --
ADDED :
* XY Chart support
* &quot;Manual&quot; or &quot;Auto&quot; trial start mode support
* Content proposal enhancement on Functional and Conditional
blocks
FIXED :
* Nothing
-- 2019-06-10 --
ADDED :
* properties.0.name = org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description and
value in order to provide update information to user
* This text on Information Docometre.feature page
FIXED :
* Nothing
   </description>

   <copyright url="http://www.cecill.info/licences/Licence_CeCILL_V2.1-en.html">
      See Licence Agreement
   </copyright>

   <license url="http://www.cecill.info/licences/Licence_CeCILL_V2.1-en.html">
      CeCILL FREE SOFTWARE LICENSE AGREEMENT

Version 2.1 dated 2013-06-21


    Notice

This Agreement is a Free Software license agreement that is the result
of discussions between its authors in order to ensure compliance with
the two main principles guiding its drafting:

  * firstly, compliance with the principles governing the distribution
    of Free Software: access to source code, broad rights granted to users,
  * secondly, the election of a governing law, French law, with which it
    is conformant, both as regards the law of torts and intellectual
    property law, and the protection that it offers to both authors and
    holders of the economic rights over software.

The authors of the CeCILL (for Ce[a] C[nrs] I[nria] L[ogiciel] L[ibre]) 
license are: 

Commissariat à l&apos;énergie atomique et aux énergies alternatives - CEA, a
public scientific, technical and industrial research establishment,
having its principal place of business at 25 rue Leblanc, immeuble Le
Ponant D, 75015 Paris, France.

Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique - CNRS, a public scientific
and technological establishment, having its principal place of business
at 3 rue Michel-Ange, 75794 Paris cedex 16, France.

Institut National de Recherche en Informatique et en Automatique -
Inria, a public scientific and technological establishment, having its
principal place of business at Domaine de Voluceau, Rocquencourt, BP
105, 78153 Le Chesnay cedex, France.


    Preamble

The purpose of this Free Software license agreement is to grant users
the right to modify and redistribute the software governed by this
license within the framework of an open source distribution model.

The exercising of this right is conditional upon certain obligations for
users so as to preserve this status for all subsequent redistributions.

In consideration of access to the source code and the rights to copy,
modify and redistribute granted by the license, users are provided only
with a limited warranty and the software&apos;s author, the holder of the
economic rights, and the successive licensors only have limited liability.

In this respect, the risks associated with loading, using, modifying
and/or developing or reproducing the software by the user are brought to
the user&apos;s attention, given its Free Software status, which may make it
complicated to use, with the result that its use is reserved for
developers and experienced professionals having in-depth computer
knowledge. Users are therefore encouraged to load and test the
suitability of the software as regards their requirements in conditions
enabling the security of their systems and/or data to be ensured and,
more generally, to use and operate it in the same conditions of
security. This Agreement may be freely reproduced and published,
provided it is not altered, and that no provisions are either added or
removed herefrom.

This Agreement may apply to any or all software for which the holder of
the economic rights decides to submit the use thereof to its provisions.

Frequently asked questions can be found on the official website of the
CeCILL licenses family (http://www.cecill.info/index.en.html) for any 
necessary clarification.


    Article 1 - DEFINITIONS

For the purpose of this Agreement, when the following expressions
commence with a capital letter, they shall have the following meaning:

Agreement: means this license agreement, and its possible subsequent
versions and annexes.

Software: means the software in its Object Code and/or Source Code form
and, where applicable, its documentation, &quot;as is&quot; when the Licensee
accepts the Agreement.

Initial Software: means the Software in its Source Code and possibly its
Object Code form and, where applicable, its documentation, &quot;as is&quot; when
it is first distributed under the terms and conditions of the Agreement.

Modified Software: means the Software modified by at least one
Contribution.

Source Code: means all the Software&apos;s instructions and program lines to
which access is required so as to modify the Software.

Object Code: means the binary files originating from the compilation of
the Source Code.

Holder: means the holder(s) of the economic rights over the Initial
Software.

Licensee: means the Software user(s) having accepted the Agreement.

Contributor: means a Licensee having made at least one Contribution.

Licensor: means the Holder, or any other individual or legal entity, who
distributes the Software under the Agreement.

Contribution: means any or all modifications, corrections, translations,
adaptations and/or new functions integrated into the Software by any or
all Contributors, as well as any or all Internal Modules.

Module: means a set of sources files including their documentation that
enables supplementary functions or services in addition to those offered
by the Software.

External Module: means any or all Modules, not derived from the
Software, so that this Module and the Software run in separate address
spaces, with one calling the other when they are run.

Internal Module: means any or all Module, connected to the Software so
that they both execute in the same address space.

GNU GPL: means the GNU General Public License version 2 or any
subsequent version, as published by the Free Software Foundation Inc.

GNU Affero GPL: means the GNU Affero General Public License version 3 or
any subsequent version, as published by the Free Software Foundation Inc.

EUPL: means the European Union Public License version 1.1 or any
subsequent version, as published by the European Commission.

Parties: mean both the Licensee and the Licensor.

These expressions may be used both in singular and plural form.


    Article 2 - PURPOSE

The purpose of the Agreement is the grant by the Licensor to the
Licensee of a non-exclusive, transferable and worldwide license for the
Software as set forth in Article 5 &lt;#scope&gt; hereinafter for the whole
term of the protection granted by the rights over said Software.


    Article 3 - ACCEPTANCE

3.1 The Licensee shall be deemed as having accepted the terms and
conditions of this Agreement upon the occurrence of the first of the
following events:

  * (i) loading the Software by any or all means, notably, by
    downloading from a remote server, or by loading from a physical medium;
  * (ii) the first time the Licensee exercises any of the rights granted
    hereunder.

3.2 One copy of the Agreement, containing a notice relating to the
characteristics of the Software, to the limited warranty, and to the
fact that its use is restricted to experienced users has been provided
to the Licensee prior to its acceptance as set forth in Article 3.1
&lt;#accepting&gt; hereinabove, and the Licensee hereby acknowledges that it
has read and understood it.


    Article 4 - EFFECTIVE DATE AND TERM


      4.1 EFFECTIVE DATE

The Agreement shall become effective on the date when it is accepted by
the Licensee as set forth in Article 3.1 &lt;#accepting&gt;.


      4.2 TERM

The Agreement shall remain in force for the entire legal term of
protection of the economic rights over the Software.


    Article 5 - SCOPE OF RIGHTS GRANTED

The Licensor hereby grants to the Licensee, who accepts, the following
rights over the Software for any or all use, and for the term of the
Agreement, on the basis of the terms and conditions set forth hereinafter.

Besides, if the Licensor owns or comes to own one or more patents
protecting all or part of the functions of the Software or of its
components, the Licensor undertakes not to enforce the rights granted by
these patents against successive Licensees using, exploiting or
modifying the Software. If these patents are transferred, the Licensor
undertakes to have the transferees subscribe to the obligations set
forth in this paragraph.


      5.1 RIGHT OF USE

The Licensee is authorized to use the Software, without any limitation
as to its fields of application, with it being hereinafter specified
that this comprises:

 1. permanent or temporary reproduction of all or part of the Software
    by any or all means and in any or all form.

 2. loading, displaying, running, or storing the Software on any or all
    medium.

 3. entitlement to observe, study or test its operation so as to
    determine the ideas and principles behind any or all constituent
    elements of said Software. This shall apply when the Licensee
    carries out any or all loading, displaying, running, transmission or
    storage operation as regards the Software, that it is entitled to
    carry out hereunder.


      5.2 ENTITLEMENT TO MAKE CONTRIBUTIONS

The right to make Contributions includes the right to translate, adapt,
arrange, or make any or all modifications to the Software, and the right
to reproduce the resulting software.

The Licensee is authorized to make any or all Contributions to the
Software provided that it includes an explicit notice that it is the
author of said Contribution and indicates the date of the creation thereof.


      5.3 RIGHT OF DISTRIBUTION

In particular, the right of distribution includes the right to publish,
transmit and communicate the Software to the general public on any or
all medium, and by any or all means, and the right to market, either in
consideration of a fee, or free of charge, one or more copies of the
Software by any means.

The Licensee is further authorized to distribute copies of the modified
or unmodified Software to third parties according to the terms and
conditions set forth hereinafter.


        5.3.1 DISTRIBUTION OF SOFTWARE WITHOUT MODIFICATION

The Licensee is authorized to distribute true copies of the Software in
Source Code or Object Code form, provided that said distribution
complies with all the provisions of the Agreement and is accompanied by:

 1. a copy of the Agreement,

 2. a notice relating to the limitation of both the Licensor&apos;s warranty
    and liability as set forth in Articles 8 and 9,

and that, in the event that only the Object Code of the Software is
redistributed, the Licensee allows effective access to the full Source
Code of the Software for a period of at least three years from the
distribution of the Software, it being understood that the additional
acquisition cost of the Source Code shall not exceed the cost of the
data transfer.


        5.3.2 DISTRIBUTION OF MODIFIED SOFTWARE

When the Licensee makes a Contribution to the Software, the terms and
conditions for the distribution of the resulting Modified Software
become subject to all the provisions of this Agreement.

The Licensee is authorized to distribute the Modified Software, in
source code or object code form, provided that said distribution
complies with all the provisions of the Agreement and is accompanied by:

 1. a copy of the Agreement,

 2. a notice relating to the limitation of both the Licensor&apos;s warranty
    and liability as set forth in Articles 8 and 9,

and, in the event that only the object code of the Modified Software is
redistributed,

 3. a note stating the conditions of effective access to the full source
    code of the Modified Software for a period of at least three years
    from the distribution of the Modified Software, it being understood
    that the additional acquisition cost of the source code shall not
    exceed the cost of the data transfer.


        5.3.3 DISTRIBUTION OF EXTERNAL MODULES

When the Licensee has developed an External Module, the terms and
conditions of this Agreement do not apply to said External Module, that
may be distributed under a separate license agreement.


        5.3.4 COMPATIBILITY WITH OTHER LICENSES

The Licensee can include a code that is subject to the provisions of one
of the versions of the GNU GPL, GNU Affero GPL and/or EUPL in the
Modified or unmodified Software, and distribute that entire code under
the terms of the same version of the GNU GPL, GNU Affero GPL and/or EUPL.

The Licensee can include the Modified or unmodified Software in a code
that is subject to the provisions of one of the versions of the GNU GPL,
GNU Affero GPL and/or EUPL and distribute that entire code under the
terms of the same version of the GNU GPL, GNU Affero GPL and/or EUPL.


    Article 6 - INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY


      6.1 OVER THE INITIAL SOFTWARE

The Holder owns the economic rights over the Initial Software. Any or
all use of the Initial Software is subject to compliance with the terms
and conditions under which the Holder has elected to distribute its work
and no one shall be entitled to modify the terms and conditions for the
distribution of said Initial Software.

The Holder undertakes that the Initial Software will remain ruled at
least by this Agreement, for the duration set forth in Article 4.2 &lt;#term&gt;.


      6.2 OVER THE CONTRIBUTIONS

The Licensee who develops a Contribution is the owner of the
intellectual property rights over this Contribution as defined by
applicable law.


      6.3 OVER THE EXTERNAL MODULES

The Licensee who develops an External Module is the owner of the
intellectual property rights over this External Module as defined by
applicable law and is free to choose the type of agreement that shall
govern its distribution.


      6.4 JOINT PROVISIONS

The Licensee expressly undertakes:

 1. not to remove, or modify, in any manner, the intellectual property
    notices attached to the Software;

 2. to reproduce said notices, in an identical manner, in the copies of
    the Software modified or not.

The Licensee undertakes not to directly or indirectly infringe the
intellectual property rights on the Software of the Holder and/or
Contributors, and to take, where applicable, vis-à-vis its staff, any
and all measures required to ensure respect of said intellectual
property rights of the Holder and/or Contributors.


    Article 7 - RELATED SERVICES

7.1 Under no circumstances shall the Agreement oblige the Licensor to
provide technical assistance or maintenance services for the Software.

However, the Licensor is entitled to offer this type of services. The
terms and conditions of such technical assistance, and/or such
maintenance, shall be set forth in a separate instrument. Only the
Licensor offering said maintenance and/or technical assistance services
shall incur liability therefor.

7.2 Similarly, any Licensor is entitled to offer to its licensees, under
its sole responsibility, a warranty, that shall only be binding upon
itself, for the redistribution of the Software and/or the Modified
Software, under terms and conditions that it is free to decide. Said
warranty, and the financial terms and conditions of its application,
shall be subject of a separate instrument executed between the Licensor
and the Licensee.


    Article 8 - LIABILITY

8.1 Subject to the provisions of Article 8.2, the Licensee shall be
entitled to claim compensation for any direct loss it may have suffered
from the Software as a result of a fault on the part of the relevant
Licensor, subject to providing evidence thereof.

8.2 The Licensor&apos;s liability is limited to the commitments made under
this Agreement and shall not be incurred as a result of in particular:
(i) loss due the Licensee&apos;s total or partial failure to fulfill its
obligations, (ii) direct or consequential loss that is suffered by the
Licensee due to the use or performance of the Software, and (iii) more
generally, any consequential loss. In particular the Parties expressly
agree that any or all pecuniary or business loss (i.e. loss of data,
loss of profits, operating loss, loss of customers or orders,
opportunity cost, any disturbance to business activities) or any or all
legal proceedings instituted against the Licensee by a third party,
shall constitute consequential loss and shall not provide entitlement to
any or all compensation from the Licensor.


    Article 9 - WARRANTY

9.1 The Licensee acknowledges that the scientific and technical
state-of-the-art when the Software was distributed did not enable all
possible uses to be tested and verified, nor for the presence of
possible defects to be detected. In this respect, the Licensee&apos;s
attention has been drawn to the risks associated with loading, using,
modifying and/or developing and reproducing the Software which are
reserved for experienced users.

The Licensee shall be responsible for verifying, by any or all means,
the suitability of the product for its requirements, its good working
order, and for ensuring that it shall not cause damage to either persons
or properties.

9.2 The Licensor hereby represents, in good faith, that it is entitled
to grant all the rights over the Software (including in particular the
rights set forth in Article 5 &lt;#scope&gt;).

9.3 The Licensee acknowledges that the Software is supplied &quot;as is&quot; by
the Licensor without any other express or tacit warranty, other than
that provided for in Article 9.2 &lt;#good-faith&gt; and, in particular,
without any warranty as to its commercial value, its secured, safe,
innovative or relevant nature.

Specifically, the Licensor does not warrant that the Software is free
from any error, that it will operate without interruption, that it will
be compatible with the Licensee&apos;s own equipment and software
configuration, nor that it will meet the Licensee&apos;s requirements.

9.4 The Licensor does not either expressly or tacitly warrant that the
Software does not infringe any third party intellectual property right
relating to a patent, software or any other property right. Therefore,
the Licensor disclaims any and all liability towards the Licensee
arising out of any or all proceedings for infringement that may be
instituted in respect of the use, modification and redistribution of the
Software. Nevertheless, should such proceedings be instituted against
the Licensee, the Licensor shall provide it with technical and legal
expertise for its defense. Such technical and legal expertise shall be
decided on a case-by-case basis between the relevant Licensor and the
Licensee pursuant to a memorandum of understanding. The Licensor
disclaims any and all liability as regards the Licensee&apos;s use of the
name of the Software. No warranty is given as regards the existence of
prior rights over the name of the Software or as regards the existence
of a trademark.


    Article 10 - TERMINATION

10.1 In the event of a breach by the Licensee of its obligations
hereunder, the Licensor may automatically terminate this Agreement
thirty (30) days after notice has been sent to the Licensee and has
remained ineffective.

10.2 A Licensee whose Agreement is terminated shall no longer be
authorized to use, modify or distribute the Software. However, any
licenses that it may have granted prior to termination of the Agreement
shall remain valid subject to their having been granted in compliance
with the terms and conditions hereof.


    Article 11 - MISCELLANEOUS


      11.1 EXCUSABLE EVENTS

Neither Party shall be liable for any or all delay, or failure to
perform the Agreement, that may be attributable to an event of force
majeure, an act of God or an outside cause, such as defective
functioning or interruptions of the electricity or telecommunications
networks, network paralysis following a virus attack, intervention by
government authorities, natural disasters, water damage, earthquakes,
fire, explosions, strikes and labor unrest, war, etc.

11.2 Any failure by either Party, on one or more occasions, to invoke
one or more of the provisions hereof, shall under no circumstances be
interpreted as being a waiver by the interested Party of its right to
invoke said provision(s) subsequently.

11.3 The Agreement cancels and replaces any or all previous agreements,
whether written or oral, between the Parties and having the same
purpose, and constitutes the entirety of the agreement between said
Parties concerning said purpose. No supplement or modification to the
terms and conditions hereof shall be effective as between the Parties
unless it is made in writing and signed by their duly authorized
representatives.

11.4 In the event that one or more of the provisions hereof were to
conflict with a current or future applicable act or legislative text,
said act or legislative text shall prevail, and the Parties shall make
the necessary amendments so as to comply with said act or legislative
text. All other provisions shall remain effective. Similarly, invalidity
of a provision of the Agreement, for any reason whatsoever, shall not
cause the Agreement as a whole to be invalid.


      11.5 LANGUAGE

The Agreement is drafted in both French and English and both versions
are deemed authentic.


    Article 12 - NEW VERSIONS OF THE AGREEMENT

12.1 Any person is authorized to duplicate and distribute copies of this
Agreement.

12.2 So as to ensure coherence, the wording of this Agreement is
protected and may only be modified by the authors of the License, who
reserve the right to periodically publish updates or new versions of the
Agreement, each with a separate number. These subsequent versions may
address new issues encountered by Free Software.

12.3 Any Software distributed under a given version of the Agreement may
only be subsequently distributed under the same version of the Agreement
or a subsequent version, subject to the provisions of Article 5.3.4
&lt;#compatibility&gt;.


    Article 13 - GOVERNING LAW AND JURISDICTION

13.1 The Agreement is governed by French law. The Parties agree to
endeavor to seek an amicable solution to any disagreements or disputes
that may arise during the performance of the Agreement.

13.2 Failing an amicable solution within two (2) months as from their
occurrence, and unless emergency proceedings are necessary, the
disagreements or disputes shall be referred to the Paris Courts having
jurisdiction, by the more diligent Party.
   </license>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.rcp"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.core.feature"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.user.ui"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.extras.feature"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.rcp.feature"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.help"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.emf.common"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.emf.ecore"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.ecf.filetransfer.feature"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <includes
         id="org.eclipse.ecf.core.feature"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="Docometre"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.concurrent"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.ui.importexport"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.forms"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="javax.el"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="DocometreHelp"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.cheatsheets"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.intro"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.intro.universal"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.jface.text"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.text"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="ADWin"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="Log4J"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.views"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="Process"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="JOGL"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.core.expressions"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.jface.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.swt.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.workbench.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.e4.ui.workbench.renderers.swt.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.ui.sdk.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.ui.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.ui.sdk.scheduler.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.cheatsheets.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.intro.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.intro.universal.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.help.webapp.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.help.base.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.help.ui.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.p2.operations.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.core.resources"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.gef"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="RTSWTChart"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.core.filesystem"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.draw2d"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.intro.quicklinks"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.gef.translations"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="JSSC"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.equinox.event"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.swtchart"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.swtchart.extensions"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="MatlabController"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="MatlabEngine"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="py4j-java"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="PythonController"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.ui.themes"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.e4.ui.css.swt.theme"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.nebula.visualization.widgets"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.nebula.visualization.xygraph"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="JMatIO"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="MigLayoutSwing"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="OpenCSV"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="PLY"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="JZY3D"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.swt.tools"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.swt.tools.base"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

   <plugin
         id="org.eclipse.swt.tools.spies"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="com.google.guava"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="jakarta.servlet-api"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="Libraries"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

</feature>
