<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Quick Start Guide">
	<intro>
		<description>
			<b>Welcome in this Quick Start Tutorial.</b><br/><br/>
			You will learn how to create an experiment based on an ADWin Gold
			hardware configuration. Then you will add a Subject to this
			experiment. This Subject will contain one session with ten trials.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Create an experiment">
		<description>
			Select menu item
			<b>File &gt; New &gt; Experiment</b>
			<br />
			Enter &quot;
			<b>NewExperiment</b>
			&quot; as experiment name and an optional description of this
			experiment. You could type &quot;
			<b>Quick start tutorial experiment</b>
			&quot; for instance.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Select created experiment">
		<description>
			In the Experiments View, select this new created experiment. If the
			Experiments View is not visible, then select menu item
			<b>Window > Show > Experiments View</b>
			and select the new created experiment in this view.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Add an hardware configuration">
		<description>
			Select menu item
			<b>File &gt; New &gt; DACQ Configuration</b>
			<br />
			Enter "
			<b>ADWinGold</b>
			" as DACQ configuration name, "
			<b>ADWinGold hardware configuration</b>
			" as optional description and select <b>ADWin</b> as configuration, then
			click
			<b>Finish</b>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Configure this DACQ Configuration">
		<description>
			Open this newly created DACQ file (double click on the file or right click and click on menu item <b>Open</b>)
			<br />
			Browse to <b>ADBasicCompiler</b> executable and <b>ADWin9</b> bootloader to specify these absolute paths. Depending on your ADWin System, it could also be <b>ADWinA</b> or <b>ADWinB</b> bootloader.
			<br/>
			<b>Libraries Path</b> must point to the <b>ADWinIncludeFiles</b> folder which is in you Docometre installation directory. Configure this absolute path if not already done.
			<br/>
			Then select the <b>ADBasic version</b> you have.
			<br/>
			If you don't plan to use <b>ADWin TCPIP server</b>, do not modify the TCPIP server number. Change it accordingly to your needs if you plan to access ADWin system over this TCPIP server.
			<br/>
			You must then specify ADwin Gold <b>IP address</b> (often something like 192.168.0.x), <b>TCPIP port</b> (generally 6543) and the <b>Device number</b> specified when you installed ADWinGold using ADConfig.
			<br/>
			You can left unchanged Time out value to 1s. Select Gold as Device type and I as CPU type. Of course, these two last parameters depend on your hardware systems (ADwinPro/Gold, CPU I/II).
			<br/>
			Leave Global frequency to 2KHz.
			<br/>
			In <b>Module Configuration Panel</b>, you should at least have one line with an analog inputs module, just specify the correct module revision number and double click on the line or select "Analog inputs #1" panel.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Configure Analog input module">
		<description>
			In this panel you will have to configure some global module parameters and some others specific to an analog input.
			<br />
			<b>Global module parameters</b><br />
			Here you will have to select the CAN range : &#177;10V, &#177;5V or [0-10]V.<br />
			<b>Analog input</b><br />
			In the <b>Channels Configuration</b> section title bar, click on add icon to add an analog input channel.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Add an Oscillo. Chart">
		<description>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Create a 10s acquisition process">
		<description>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Test this process">
		<description>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Add a subject with a session of ten trials">
		<description>
			In the Experiments View, select the created experiment then
			select menu item
			<b>File &gt; New &gt; Subject</b>
			<br />
			Enter &quot;
			<b>John_DOE</b>
			&quot; as subject name and an optional description, then click
			<b>Finish</b>
			<br />
			Select &quot;
			<b>John_DOE</b>
			&quot; Subject in the experiment view, then select menu item
			<b>File &gt; New &gt; Session</b>
			<br />
			Enter &quot;
			<b>Session1</b>
			&quot; as session name, an optional description and ten as trials
			number, then click
			<b>Finish</b>
			<br />
		</description>
	</item>

</cheatsheet>
